<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="introduction">
   <title>Introduction</title>

   <para>Have you ever found yourself frustrated with a ClassNotFoundException? 
     Would you like to know what libraries are in your project and what they depend on? 
     Would you like to get a full report on this stuff every time you run your ant build? 
     If so you need to use the JBoss Tattletale project!</para>

   <para>JBoss Tattletale is a tool that can help you get an overview of the project you are 
     working on or a product that you depend on.</para>

   <para>The tool will provide you with reports that can help you</para>
   <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
     <listitem>
       <para>Identify dependencies between JAR files</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Find missing classes from the classpath</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Spot if a class/package is located in multiple JAR files</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Spot if the same JAR file is located in multiple locations</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>With a list of what each JAR file requires and provides</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Verify the SerialVersionUID of a class</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Find similar JAR files that have different version numbers</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Find JAR files without a version number</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Find unused JAR files</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Identify sealed and signed JAR archives</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Locate a class in a JAR file</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Get the OSGi status of your project</para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>And generate the same reports for your .WAR and .EAR archives</para>
     </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>

   <para>JBoss Tattletale will recursive scan the directory pass as the argument for JAR files and then
     build the reports as HTML files.</para>

   <para>JBoss Tattletale is licensed under GNU Lesser General Public License (LGPL) version 2.1 or later.</para>

   <para>We hope that JBoss Tattletale will help you in your development tasks !</para>

   <para>Please, visit the official JBoss Tattletale project page at 
     <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/tattletale/">http://www.jboss.org/tattletale/</ulink>.</para>

</chapter>
