<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="troubleshooting">
   <title>Troubleshooting</title>

   <section id="noreports">
      <title>JBoss Tattletale generates empty reports</title>

      <para>JBoss Tattletale generates its reports based on Java archives and not source code. Make sure that 
      sourcedir you specify when running JBoss Tattletale contains the Java archives (f.ex. .JAR files) that you
      need scanned.</para>

   </section>

   <section id="oom">
      <title>JBoss Tattletale throws an OutOfMemoryException</title>

      <para>JBoss Tattletale needs to process the information it gathers in memory, so you need to provide enough
        memory for that to happen. You can ajust the -Xmx parameter of the command line below if you are using 
      Sun's Java Runtime Environment.</para>

     <programlisting>
java -Xmx1024m -jar jboss-tattletale.jar &lt;sourcedir&gt; [&lt;outputdir&gt;]
     </programlisting>

   </section>

   <section id="iwouldliketoimplementafeature">
      <title>I would like to implement a feature</title>

      <para>So you have found an area where you are missing a feature and would like to submit a patch for it, great !</para>

      <para>There are a couple of steps to get a feature included</para>

      <para>First, you should create a new thread in our 
        <ulink url="http://community.jboss.org/en/tattletale/dev">development forum</ulink> where you describe
        the feature, its design and implementation.</para>

      <para>Once there is an agreement on the feature and the design you should proceed with creating the patch.</para>

      <para>To maximize your chances of getting the feature in the official build as soon as possible make sure that
        you run <code>checkstyle</code> to make sure that the code is correctly formatted:</para>

      <programlisting>
ant clean checkstyle
      </programlisting>

      <para>when there are no errors, create a JIRA task (Feature) in our 
        <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/browse/TTALE">JIRA environment</ulink> and attach the patch. 
        See the developer guide for additional details.</para>

      <para>Happy Coding !</para>

   </section>

   <section id="howdoi">
      <title>How do I ?</title>

      <para>We can't cover every single issue in this guide, so feel free to drop by our forums to see if a solution
        has already been provided. Otherwise feel free to ask your question there.</para>

      <para>Our forum is located at <ulink url="http://community.jboss.org/en/tattletale"/>.</para>

   </section>
   
</chapter>
